currys.co.uk 2015-09-06

# Cookie Guide & Privacy Information | Currys

    * Built-in appliances
    * Brand shop
    * Services
    * Brand shops
    * Brand shops
    * Learn more about
    * Brand shops
    * Learn more about
    * Brand shops
    * Services
    * Brand shops
    * Learn more about
    * Brand shops
    * Learn more about
    * Brand shops
    * Learn more about
    * Brand shops
    * Learn more about

## Privacy & Cookies

  * What are Cookies?
  *  
  * Currys & Cookies
  *  
  * Cookie Control
  *  
  * Advertising
  *  
  * Privacy on Currys

### The Ingredients of a Cookie

When you are browsing websites on the internet, many of these websites store tiny text files called cookies on your computer, to help track your use of the site and to personalise your journey around the website. These cookies can be stored so that if you return to a website, that website server can call the information from the cookies stored on your computer to tailor your experience of the site. 

Currys.co.uk is no different, we use cookies to help you shop our website more effectively and to place online orders - we do not store personally identifiable information in our cookie data. We also use some carefully selected 3rd party suppliers to enhance your online experience and they will place cookies on your computer for use on our website too. 

Cookies are perfectly safe to be stored on your computer and almost all web browsers have cookie storing enabled as default. However, all browsers have the option of disabling cookies being stored on your computer if you wish to do this.

Please be aware that disabling cookies on your browser will reduce your ability to shop online with Currys.co.uk. We use cookies to process products in your basket and orders. Disabling your cookies will mean you cannot purchase through our website. This would also be a common experience of reduced functionality across many websites. 

To learn about how change the cookie settings for your browser on our Cookie Control page. 

Recent legislation from the European Union has meant that websites must provide clear information about their use of cookies to their customers, something we at Currys fully support. We want to ensure that you, as our valued customer, are fully aware of the use of cookies on our website, and we are proud of our reputation as a transparent and honest retailer that you can trust. 

### Currys & Cookies

We want to make sure you are fully aware of the cookies we use and what they do when you are shopping on Currys.co.uk. 

Here is a full guide to our cookies explaining the name of the cookie as it would appear on your computer, a description of what the cookie is used for and a rating from our technical teams on level of information held:

**Cookie Name** | **Description of Cookie usage**  
---|---  
Rich Relevance | 

Rich Relevance is one of our approved suppliers that create recommendations on our website for our customers based on their journey through our site and the products they are interested in. They use cookies to display products of interest to you such as ‘Customers who viewed this also viewed’ or ‘Items commonly purchased with this product’.  
  
sCountryCode | A cookie containing 2 characters that remains persistent for 1 month containing “GB” to ensure correct web pages are displayed to you based on the country you are browsing from.  
sLanguageCode | A session ID cookie that expires after 20 minutes if your web browser is not closed. By storing your session, we can maintain your basket and its contents for longer during session.  
cookieSource2 | A cookie containing 2 characters that remains persistent for 1 month containing “UK” to ensure correct translation module is displayed for appropriate content language.  
Google Analytics (_utXX) | 

We use Google Analytics to help provide us data about the way our customers use our websites to improve your experience. Google Analytics cookies record visitors, city locations, browser type and site journey. Google Analytics cookies do not record personal information. For a full description of Google’s use of cookies please visit: 

<http://code.google.com/apis/analytics/docs/concepts/gaConceptsCookies.html>  
  
Google adwords conversion tracking | 

Our source cookie contains PHP data containing the last 3 traffic sources (referring website) associated to the customer. This cookie helps us understand relevant related websites. This cookie contains no user-specific details or information. 

This is a cookie from Google that helps us to understand how customers are purchasing from our website. This information helps us understand what is working more successfully for us in terms of sponsored advertising on search engines, website structures, promotions and other key identifiers. The cookie does not contain any personal information about our customers. 

[https://support.google.com/adwords/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=93148](https://support.google.com/adwords/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=93148)  
  
Affiliate Window (awXXXX) | 

An Affiliate Window cookie is used to track websites that are sending customers to our website from theirs so that we can reward them for the referral. When a customer clicks through to our website from an affiliate site a cookie is dropped on that website’s server. When the customer actually arrives on our site, we drop a cookie onto your computer to track the source and the destination. There is only ever 1 Affiliate Window cookie on your PC per transaction. The cookie is retained for 30 days. 

Affiliate Window cookies are marked awXXXX where XXXX is the ID of the website referring the visitor to our website according to Affiliate Window. An Affiliate Window cookie captures click date/time, IP address, affiliate ID, click reference, product ID. 

Further information provided in terms of guidance from Affiliate Window in the document below.

SaleCycle | 

SaleCycle collect information to enable us to send bespoke service emails to customers that cannot complete their checkout journey. To opt out of SaleCycle tracking, please visit: 

<http://www.salecycle.com/privacy-policy>

This will drop a persistent cookie on your machine, blocking the use of SaleCycle tracking. If you delete this cookie, the tracking will resume.  
  
Walker Media | 

We currently use 49 persistent cookies (70 planned) that are compiled from various approved suppliers used to collect data on sales and revenue based on advertising activity, retargeting of advertising and offers. All data collected is anonymous and with no intervention the tags will persist on your computer for 24 months. 

The relevant privacy policies from the companies are below: 

Mediaplex: <http://www.mediaplex.com/mojo-privacy-statement>

AdGenie: <http://www.geniegroupltd.co.uk/Genie/364608/privacy_policy.html>

Criteo: <http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy>  
  
Site Tagger for Adobe Site Catalyst and Test and Target | 

We use 5 session cookies through Site Tagger, an approved supplier, that relate to the use of Adobe Omniture Site Catalyst, another approved supplier. The details of the cookies are below:

  * s_searchT – this cookie is used to store the search term that the customer has used on the website
  * s_intcmp – this cookies stores the title of the internal campaign (promotion) the customer has used
  * deliveryCost – this cookie stores the delivery cost of our item(s)
  * stvisited – this cookie determines whether the customer has already added something to the basket
  * promocode – this cookie stores the promotional code used (if any) by a customer

Data is consumed and used by the Site Catalyst reporting suite therefore will need to refer to information from Adobe around data usage. 

<http://www.adobe.com/uk/privacy/cookies.html>  
  
PriceRunner | 

PriceRunner is an approved supplier of ours, and they use 2 cookies in conjunction with a tracking pixel on our order confirmation page that confirms you have placed an order. Both are persistent cookies and are set to expire after 5 years:

  * s.apmebf.com/s.emjcd.com – this cookie stores the session ID along with confirmed sale details. This cookie tracks the link between an advertisement being clicked by a customer and resulting sales for the advertiser 
  * lclk.apmebt.com/lclk.emjcd.com – this cookie stores customer clicks through to sale correlation and is used to track when an advertisement is clicked on that results in a sale for the advertiser 

There is also a disclaimer of information regarding cookies from our supplier (ValueClick is the parent company for PriceRunner): 

_The information provided by ValueClick, its use and the results of such use is provided on an as is, as available basis, without any representation or endorsement made and without warranty of any kind whether express or implied. To the fullest extent permissible pursuant to applicable law, ValueClick disclaims all warranties. ValueClick is not liable for any damages arising in contract, tort or otherwise from your use of or inability to use this information or from any action or decision taken as a result of using this information. Please note that, whilst every effort is made to ensure the accuracy of the information, it is made available for general information only and is specifically directed to the recipient._  
  
Foresee | 

Foresee are an approved supplier of ours, used to gain better insight into our customer behaviours via optional surveys designed to improve our overall website experience for customers.

  * Fsr.s – this is a session level cookie used to determine whether a survey will be presented to the customer and when, only a session ID stored.
  * Fsr.r – this is a persistent cookie used to ensure customers are not invited to participate in a survey for a specific number of days, the default value is 90 days.
  * Fsr.a – this is a session level cookie used to ensure the survey is presented at the conclusion of the site experience for a customer. 

No personal information is held in any of these cookies.  
  
Reevoo | Info TBD  
ISTTrack | This cookie is from one of our approved suppliers called IS Technology used to identify a particular user/browser. The cookie persists for 30 days and only contains a randomly generated GUID (Globally unique identifier). This cookie is dropped on a customer’s computer when they interact with certain product links.  
session | A session ID cookie that expires after 20 minutes if your web browser is not closed. By storing your session, we can maintain your basket and its contents for longer during a session.  
AD2ONE | We use DoubleClick (Google) for the use of the DART cookie which enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to the site and other sites on the Internet. DoubleClick Retargeting & Optimisation Cookies allows for retargeting and exclusion of ads, as well as allowing for optimisation of campaigns through tracking conversions and expires after 30 days. 

Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy. 

Click [here](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/) for the Google privacy policy.  
  
TouchCommerce Live Chat | TouchCommerce is our live chat supplier, which uses three cookies to ensure that the live chat is fully funcational and our chat invitations are offered to the right customers at the right time. It is important to note that these cookies do not collect any personal information about our customers.

The inqState cookie is a persistent cookie used to track state-related customer information, such as whether the customer has visited the site before and how much time the customer has spent browsing our site. The inqSession cookie is a session cookie that tracks events, such as when customers navigate to other pages, when a customer interacts with one of our chat agents, and when an agent interacts with one of our customers. Lastly, the inqVital cookie is a persistent cookie which contains vital information associated with the chat itself, such as the customer ID and the status of the chat.  
  
These are all the cookies currently used by our website and our approved suppliers. Hopefully it is clear that all of our cookies are used ultimately to improve the journey for our customers online or to help us present a better website experience online. 

If you feel you would like to change your personal interaction with cookies, you can adjust storage of cookies settings through your web browser by checking out our Cookie Control page. 

_**Please be aware** _ disabling cookies will severely limit your ability to shop on Currys.co.uk and disable features of many websites across the internet. 

**Sharing our pages online**

On Currys.co.uk you are able to share certain pages with your friends and networks through 3rd party sites such as [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/help/?page=176591669064814) , [Twitter](https://twitter.com/privacy) and [Google+](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/) . If you choose to share via these networks, you may have cookies from these networks stored on your computer. These cookies are not something we control and are sent to you by the 3rd party site you share through – click the links above to learn about the network’s policy on privacy and cookies.

### Cookies Control

Cookies should be enabled by default on your browser, so if you have not changed your settings you should expect to be accepting cookies from websites. 

Cookies being disabled will limit your experience of Currys.co.uk and many other websites online. Remember, cookies are not harmful to your computer and our cookies on Currys.co.uk do not contain any personally identifiable information. If you wish to change your cookie settings we have provided a guide below for you. Please remember, if you do disable your cookies, you can allow cookies from certain approved websites, by adding the website homepage to your exceptions list. 

First, find out what your default web browser is on your machine, or the browser you use most often to access the internet. To work out what browser you are using, simply open the internet as usual, and then follow the steps below:   
v **PC Users**   
On the tool bar at the top of your browser click 'Help' and choose the 'About' option from the drop down. This will tell you the browser type and version. 

**Mac Users**   
Open the internet as usual and once open, click on the Apple icon in the top left corner and choose the 'About' option. This will again tell you the browser type and version. 

Once you know the browser you are using you can find the cookie settings using the guide below relevant for your browser:

| 

Checking your settings in Internet Explorer 8 and earlier versions

  1. Locate the 'Tools' tab on the menu areas of your browser. Click on this.  

  2. There is an option called ‘Internet Options’ on the list, select this option.  

  3. This should open a pop up box with lots of tabbed options. Select the ‘Privacy’ tab from the list.  

  4. Internet Explorer has a high, medium, low auto-adjust system for internet content handling. You can configure your own settings by clicking the advanced tab and ticking the ‘Override automatic cookie handling’  

  5. Settings above Medium will disable cookies, Medium or below will enable cookies.

---|---  
| 

Checking your settings in Mozilla Firefox

  1. Locate the 'Tools' tab on the menu areas of your browser. Click on this.   

  2. From the list of options on the drop down menu, click on ‘Options’  

  3. There should be a pop up window appear with tabs along the top. Find the ‘Privacy’ tab and select this.  

  4. You should now have some options for ‘Tracking’ and ‘History’. Under the ‘History’ drop down menu, select ‘Use customer settings for history’ if you wish to adjust your cookie settings.

| 

Checking your settings in Google Chrome

  1. Look for the spanner icon in Chrome  and click on this  

  2. From this menu, select settings...  

  3. Within settings you will see tabs on the left hand side. Select the tab called ‘Under the Hood’  

  4. When this page loads you will see a tab at the top called ‘Content Settings’ – select this  

  5. This brings up your content controls including cookie permissions – select the option you feel most comfortable with

| 

Checking your settings in Safari

  1. Locate the Cog icon at the top of your browser  and click on this.  

  2. From the list of options select ‘Preferences’  

  3. This should open a pop up window with several tabs along the top. From this list select the ‘Privacy’ option.   

  4. This will open the tab page that allows you to control the cookie settings on your browser.

| 

Checking your settings in Opera

  1. Click the Opera file icon in the top left hand corner of your browser.   

  2. From the drop down list of options, highlight ‘Settings’ and then scroll across and select ‘Preferences’.  

  3. This should open a pop up window with tabs along the top. Choose the ‘Advanced’ tab.   

  4. This shows you the advanced options. On the left hand side there is an option called ‘Cookies’ – click on this option.   

  5. This presents the cookie options for your use on this browser. 

| 

**If you have another browser...  
**

Please check the help settings within your browser or use a search engine to find answers on the best way to enable or disable cookies in your chosen browser. Please remember we are not responsible for the content on external websites.

**If you want more information...  
**

You can visit the following website for an in-depth guide to cookies and how to control, delete and understand them. They even have a great recipe on there for cookies of the edible variety – yum! 

<http://www.aboutcookies.org/>  
  
### Banner Advertising & Tags

In addition to the list of cookies that we use on Currys, we wanted to take you through our use of advertising tags. We use tags from 3rd party suppliers dedicated to helping us improve the relevance of our advertising banners, both on our website and across the web where we have advertisements on other websites. Our advertising policy is designed to give you the most relevant adverts possible, based on your previous visits to our website and the things you looked at and/or added to your basket, so we can build a profile of what we think you might like to see on our website next time you visit. A tag is simply a way for us to identify if a specific page was viewed by a customer and use that information to form a more accurate advertising strategy. 

Many online businesses work with such partners as ours below in order to improve and personalise the experience their customers have of their website and brand advertising online. All reputable companies, such as those we choose to work with, have very strict policies around your privacy and the information captured. They do not collect any information that can personally identify you in any way. Almost all of these tracking tags can be disabled or opted out of. A website dedicated to helping you understand what networks currently use tracking tags on your machine is: 

<http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>

Here you can see the companies that gather information for advertising online and choose to turn off their tracking if you wish. Please not we are not responsible for the content or activity of this website. 

Below we have listed the 3rd Party companies that use tags on our website and across the web to serve our adverts to you, our customers, with steps to disable their tracking if you wish to opt-out of their service:

ADGENIE

ADGENIE collect information to serve more targeted adverts to our customers around the web. They do not store any personally identifiable information. To opt out of ADGENIE tracking, visit 

<http://adverts.adgenie.co.uk/trackerOptOut.php>

This will drop a persistent cookie on your machine, blocking the use of tracking. If you delete this cookie, the tracking will resume.

Criteo

Criteo use information gathered from our customer’s use of our site to show more relevant adverts to you on other websites where we advertise. They do not collect any personally identifiable information from customers. To opt out of Criteo ad tracking, visit 

<http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy>

Then click on the Opt-out switch and change it to ‘On’. This will drop a cookie on your machine to remove the use of their tracking. If you delete this cookie, the tracking will resume.

MediaPlex

MediaPlex gather information to serve targeted advertisements to our customers online, just as Criteo and ADGENIE do. Again, they do not gather any personally identifiable information. To opt out of MediaPlex tracking please visit: 

<http://www.mediaplex.com/opt-out>

Click on ‘Install the MediaPlex Opt-Out Cookie. This will install a cookie to disable tracking from MediaPlex. If you delete this cookie, the tracking will resume.

MediaMind 

MediaMind install a cookie to enable advertisement personalisation online for our customers. To opt out of their advertisement tracking please visit: 

<http://www.mediamind.com/privacy-policy>

Scroll down to The Opt-Out Cookie & Your Choices section and click on the relevant link to opt out of their tracking. This will install a cookie to block the tracking of your activity online by MediaMind. If you delete this cookie, the tracking will resume.

Quantcast

Quantcast help to develop our audience for retargeting by tracking customer visits to our pages and compiling a list of our customers that can be retargeted with more personalised ads. No personally identifiable information is captured. If you would like to opt-out of Quantcast tracking, please visit: 

<http://www.quantcast.com/how-we-do-it/consumer-choice/opt-out/>

This will drop a cookie on your computer to stop the Quantcast tracking on your computer. If you delete this cookie, the tracking will resume.

AudienceScience

AudienceScience help us develop a better understanding for customer behaviour on our website and improve our overall experience for customers viewing our advertising banners online. They do not gather any personally identifiable information. If you wish to opt-out of AudienceScience tracking, please visit: 

<http://www.audiencescience.com/privacy>

Then click the link to opt-out. This will drop a cookie that will stop the tracking of your activity by AudienceScience. If you delete this cookie, the tracking will resume.

### Privacy on Currys

Is shopping online with Currys safe?

At Currys, we care about security and make every effort to ensure our transaction process is safe and that your personal information is secure. 

We can assure you that every order you make on our website is safe. We use strict security precautions to make our website safe, including the use of a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) server. Any information you enter while you're using the secure server is encrypted before being transmitted, so it is virtually impossible for an outside party to access or intercept your information. 

You can check that you are shopping in a secure environment by looking for either a locked padlock icon or an image of a key in the bar at the bottom of your screen. Additionally, your web address should start with https: - the ‘s’ indicating it is a secure page. This should appear on any page where you are entering personal information, such as your payment card details. 

The latest versions of the most popular browsers, Internet Explorer, Chrome, Safari and Firefox support this secure connection. If for any reason this option has been disabled on your browser, you will not be able to transact or login until you reset these options. Find this option in your browser settings under security.

How do you protect my credit card details and personal information?

Our website is verified by Norton Secure, powered by Verisign to protect your personal data. Your payment methods are also covered through MasterCard Secure Code or Verified by Visa. 

For your additional security and to protect your personal information we request that you enter your password each time you wish to view a page containing your personal details. 

You can enrol your card in MasterCard SecureCode or Verified by Visa scheme if you are not already a part of them. You will be able to set a private code for online transactions, giving you added protection against the unauthorised use of your credit or debit card online. 

The full details of our Privacy Policy are below in our official Privacy Policy. This policy will explain all about what information we collect from you, how we use that information and your rights around retrieving or removing any information we hold in relation to you, as well as our complete guide to the use of cookies on our website.

Our Privacy Policy

Last updated: 07.08.2012

  * Who we are
  * What information we collect and how
  * What we do with your information
  * Your rights
  * Other websites

Who we are

In this Privacy Policy references to ‘we’ and ‘us’ are to DSG Retail Limited trading as Currys, PC World and Knowhow, company number 504877, registered office Maylands Avenue, Hemel Hempstead, Hertfordshire HP2 7TG.

What information we collect and how

The information we collect via this website may include:

(1) Any personal details you type in and submit, such as name, address, email address, etc. We only collect information that we require for completion of orders and account set up. We never store payment details on the websites. 

(2) Data which allows us to recognise you, your preferences (including items added to your basket) and how you use this website. This saves you from re-entering information when you return to the site. This data is collected by cookies from your navigation around the site. A complete guide to our cookies policy and how to control cookies on your computer can be found [here](http://www.currys.co.uk/gbuk/privacy-on-currys-321-commercial.html#tab-2) . 

(3) Your IP address (this is your computer’s individual identification number) which is automatically logged by our web server. This is used to note your interest in our website and your location (e.g. county/city) for our site analytics. 

(4) Your preferences and use of email updates, recorded by emails we send you (if you select to receive email updates on products and offers).

What we do with your information

Any personal information we collect from you will be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable laws. The details we collect will be used: 

(1) to process your order, to process any application for finance or a mobile phone contract etc, to maintain guarantee records and to provide pre and after-sales service (we may pass your details to another organisation to supply/deliver products or services you have purchased and/or to provide pre or after-sales service). We make use of the TouchCommerce system to provide our web chat functionality. Data provided via web chat may be stored on servers based in the United States under a "safe harbour agreement". This means that the data will be managed to similar standards to those required under UK Data Protection legislation; and 

(2) to carry out security checks (this may involve passing your details to our Identity Verification partner, currently 192.com, who will check details we give them against public and private databases - this helps to protect you and us from fraudulent transactions); and 

(3) to comply with legal requirements   
We are a subsidiary of Dixons Carphone plc and we may need to pass the information we collect to other companies within our group for administrative purposes. We may use third parties to carry out certain activities, such as processing and sorting data, monitoring how customers use our site and issuing our emails for us. 

We would also like to inform you of various promotions, goods and services that may be of interest to you. These would come from any of our chains, including Currys, PC World, Carphone Warehouse and Knowhow, from our affiliates, or from carefully selected third parties. You may be contacted by post, email, telephone, SMS or such other means as we regard as appropriate, including new technology. If you wish to receive these communications, please tick the ‘Yes’ box when entering your personal details. You may unsubscribe at a later date, if you wish - ‘Your rights’ section below.

Your rights

(1) You can ask us to update your personal information by emailing precise details of your request to [customer.services@currys.co.uk](mailto:customer.services@currys.co.uk) .

(2) You can ask us not to send you future marketing communications. To do this, simply click this [link](https://dixonsregistration.co.uk/permoptout/?referrer=3) and submit your details.

We will then suppress your data from all direct marketing, although we will still keep it for processing your order and fulfilling customer service and after sale obligations. Alternatively, you can post your request to the address in (3) below.

(3) You also have the right to request a copy of any personal information we hold about you. To do this, simply write to us at the following address. Please enclose a cheque for £10 payable to DSG Retail Limited to cover our administration costs and proof of ID such as a copy of your driving licence or a recent utility bill:

Subject Access Request   
Legal Services  
DSG Retail Limited  
Maylands Avenue  
Hemel Hempstead  
Hertfordshire  
HP2 7TG

Other Websites

This privacy policy only covers this website. Any other websites which may be linked to by our website are subject to their own policy, which may differ from ours.
